In this segment we're going to take a moment to talk about the benefits of Qigong breathing.
The essence of all Qigong exercises is in the exercise of the breath, and although there's wonderful energetic reasons on why we do the particular Qigong exercises we do, I like to talk more about the Western physiological reasons of why the belly breathing that we often times do is so beneficial.
One of the main reasons is the lymphatic system of our body.
The lymphatic system has two pumps.
One we get through exercise, muscle contraction, and the other one is through the action of the diaphragm, the muscle that we're supposed to use in respiration.
The dome shaped muscle that's here, right underneath our lungs, and then when we breathe in it comes down and when we breathe out it comes up.
That action of the diaphragm actually moves two thirds of the lymphatic fluids of our body, lymph being, I hate to say it, the gook of our body, or the waste products of many of our body's systems.
So, one of the best way we can do a cleanse or to feel better and more energized is just through breathing.
It has other benefits where in that it actually works towards helping regulate the PH of our blood, which can be beneficial for preventing osteoporosis, and so although the calcium in our bones is the primary way, the breathing is the second most common way for our body to treat that.
So, we can actually have benefits of preventing osteoporosis just by breathing properly.
Will also be helping with all that shack neck and shoulder pain that we often get from stress breathing, that we'll talk about in the next segment.
So remember, belly breathe is the way we're supposed to breathe.